<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</title>
    <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/authors/zhu/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/authors/zhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Neurobiology lab in Hiroshima University</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:51:31 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/authors/zhu/avatar_hud1d5f3a4311afb7ce5838c0b3f54f6db_21333_270x270_fill_q90_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/authors/zhu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New study on a novel microscope for 3D visualization of the brain structure with deep ultraviolet light</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20201029/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:51:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20201029/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deciphering the connectivity between brain regions is critical in understanding how the brain works. Three dimensional visualization of such networks of the neurons has been hampered by poor penetration of visible light into the large brain tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;duv.png&#34; alt=&#34;Deep UV light&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this, our group combined the serial sectioning of the tissue block to expose new surface of the brain with scanning by light. Collected image would be used for three dimensional reconstruction of the brain structure later in the offiline analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.10.27.342345v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deep ultraviolet light based wide-field fluorescence microscope for brain imaging, preprint available in bioRxiv (doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.27.342345)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since visible light excites the fluorescent label out of focus, which makes the image blurred, we applied light to a limited optical plane at the surface of the exposed tissue block. Deep ultraviolet (DUV) light loses its power quickly after it reaches at the plane within 10-20 µm from the surface so that the image consists of the emitted light coming from the plane in focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;schematics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Workflow in DUV imaging&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is combined with motorized optics which enables scanning wide field of view to image the large brain tissue for three dimensional reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dii.png&#34; alt=&#34;Imaging neural pathways in the animals brain&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We applied this technique to the brain samples of small animals expressing green fluorescent protein and lipophilic dye in the neural pathways of mice and zebrafish. We are currently screening the fluorescent proteins and dyes compatible with this technology to widen the area for further application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, DUV imaging is quite cost-effective according to the simplicity of the optical setup. This is advantageous for the high throughput analyses with multple setups in the lab over the pre-existing expensive solution such as light-sheet and two-photon microscopies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication on dopamine transmission in stress-coping behavior</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200829/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 17:47:48 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200829/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently published a paper on a role of neurotransmitter dopamine in stress-coping behavior in Journal of Neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jneurosci.org/content/early/2020/08/26/JNEUROSCI.0444-20.2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our publication in the Journal of Neurosience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the animals encounter the environmental threat as stressor, we can think of two distinct strategies to cope with it. One is to try to overcome it by exploring actively and be against it, the other is to avoid and refrain from being close to it passively. Active and passive coping of the stress would be the basis to determine the behavioral strategies upon exposure to the stressor. Since maladaptation to the stress predispose the psychiatric disorders such as depression and anxiety, understanding the molecular mechanism underlying it is indispensable for the development of therapeutic intervention for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this, we focused on neurotransmitter dopamine which plays pivotal roles in decision making and reinforcement of the behaviors. We developed a fine carbon fiber electrode to scan the brain region called nucleus accumbens to examine how the dopamine release change when the mice changed stress-coping behaviors under the inescapable stress such as tail suspension. We found that reduction of dopamine release in this area precede the initation of escape behavior, implicating the dopaminergic transmission to the decision making under the stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fscv.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sub-milli second measurement of extracellular dopamine by fast scanning cyclic voltammetry&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check the causal effect of reduced dopamine release on mouse behaviors, we took two indepdent strategies. Optogenetic inhibitoin of dopaminergic fibers in the nucleus accumbens allowed inhibition of dopamine release at any time you want thru illumination of blue light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;optogenetics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Optogenetic manupulatin of the dopaminergic pathway&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tool we used this time is CRISPR/Cas9 which deletes the receptors for dopaminergic transmission efficiently in the mouse brain by way of viral vector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;crispr.png&#34; alt=&#34;In vivo genome editing of dopaminergic receptors by CRISPR/Cas9 technology &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both experiments proved that impaired dopaminergic transmission caused induction of escape behavior during tail suspension stress. Through this study, we are pleased to establish three important tools which must be useful for futre study: fast scanning cyclic voltammetry, optogenetics and CRISPR/Cas9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to discuss these new tools in the post comming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International collaboration</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200613/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 06:04:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We welcome the international students and collaboration to facilitate our progress in neuroscience. With the international background in Hiroshima, our lab encourages the students and researcher to develop their careers by scholarship and grants. Indeed, our lab members from a variety of countries all over the world weekly hold the meeting for the progress report and journal club. We also discuss the textbook to help the international students to understand the basics in neuroscience, optics and data science periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;member.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lab members from the countries all over the world&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, our research is enpowered by collaborations with researcher all over the world. For example, we have invited the researcher from US, UK and China to discuss and perform experiments together to develop new technologies in neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an international and research university, Hiroshima university helps the students and researcher who do not speak Japanese to learn Japanese and Japanese culture through specific classes and socials (international luncheon parties).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/#contact&#34;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in joining us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scholarship supporting the graduate course in Hiroshima</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200601/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 22:18:03 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200601/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our lab currently work with six graduate students in total. Scholarship and support by the university primarily allow them to concentrate on their own project for the theses. We were pleased to see the students win the scholarship based on their achievement to develop the carreer in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our recent review paper recognized as one of the most downloaded paper!!</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200501/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 19:04:28 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200501/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wrote a review paper in Psychiatry and Clinical Neuroscience on a role of the habenula in depressioin. This is a recent update of the small brain structure called habenula in modulation of the mood in our daily life by graduate student Zhu-san and me. We are happy to hear that our paper turned out to be one of the most downloaded paper in the journal during 2018-2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
