<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>広島大学 |　神経生物学教室（相澤研究室） | 精神神経疾患の脳科学的理解へ向けてモデル動物で分子レベルの解明を目指します</title>
    <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/authors/giga/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/authors/giga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>広島大学 |　神経生物学教室（相澤研究室） | 精神神経疾患の脳科学的理解へ向けてモデル動物で分子レベルの解明を目指します</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><copyright>© 2020 Neurobiology lab in Hiroshima University</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:06:31 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/authors/giga/avatar_hu8a197cc611ca09cf8222b65324bb2216_60756_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>広島大学 |　神経生物学教室（相澤研究室） | 精神神経疾患の脳科学的理解へ向けてモデル動物で分子レベルの解明を目指します</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/authors/giga/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New gene acting on microglia activated upon sepsis which needs critical care medicine.</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/post.bk/20201221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:06:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/post.bk/20201221/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stressors such as surgery, infection and injury lead to the pathological condition known as sepsis. Associate with the systemic inflammation, not only the visceral organs but the brain starts to respond and behave in an unusual way. Sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. The development of an effective strategy for early diagnosis and therapeutic intervention is essential for the prevention of poor prognosis of SAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO) is a mitochondrial protein implicated in inflammatory responses. Despite accumulating evidence that implicates TSPO in the neuroinflammatory response of the central nervous system, the possible role of TSPO in SAE remains unclear. In the current study, we addressed a role of TSPO in neuroinflammation using mice 24 h after systemic injection of lipopolysaccharide (LPS), which consistently demonstrated microglial activation and behavioral inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiroshi Giga, Bin Ji, Kazuya Kikutani, Shuji Fukuda, Takashi Kitajima, Seishi Katsumata, Miho Matsumata, Tetsuya Suhara, Shigeto Yamawaki, Nobuaki Shime, Koji Hosokawa, Hidenori Aizawa &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pharmacological and Genetic Inhibition of Translocator Protein 18 kDa Ameliorated Neuroinflammation in Murine Endotoxemia Model&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; SHOCK (20) &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33351449/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[PubMed]&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.lww.com/shockjournal/Abstract/9000/Pharmacological_and_Genetic_Inhibition_of.97339.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Journal website]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene expression analysis showed that TSPO in the hippomcapus was induced following the systemic LPS injection, associated with an increase in pro-inflammatory cytokines such as tumor necrosis factor-a and interleukin-1b. Interestingly, pretreatment with the TSPO antagonist, ONO-2952, or germ-line deletion of the TSPO gene exhibited an anti-inflammatory effect with significant suppression of LPS-induced production of those cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These effects of ONO-2952 or TSPO knockout were associated with significant recovery from behavioral inhibition, as shown by improved locomotor activity in the open field analysis. We also observed that ONO-2952 pretreatment suppressed the LPS-induced activation of TSPO-expressing microglia in the hippocampus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;behaviors.png&#34; alt=&#34;TSPO suppression improved behavioral alteration with systemic inflammation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how we began to understand a critical role of TSPO in SAE. Based on this finding, monitoring TSPO activity, as well as the progress of sepsis and its sequelae in the animal model, would deepen our understanding of the underlying molecular mechanism of SAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New gene acting on microglia activated upon sepsis which needs critical care medicine.</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/post/20201221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:06:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/post/20201221/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stressors such as surgery, infection and injury lead to the pathological condition known as sepsis. Associate with the systemic inflammation, not only the visceral organs but the brain starts to respond and behave in an unusual way. Sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. The development of an effective strategy for early diagnosis and therapeutic intervention is essential for the prevention of poor prognosis of SAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO) is a mitochondrial protein implicated in inflammatory responses. Despite accumulating evidence that implicates TSPO in the neuroinflammatory response of the central nervous system, the possible role of TSPO in SAE remains unclear. In the current study, we addressed a role of TSPO in neuroinflammation using mice 24 h after systemic injection of lipopolysaccharide (LPS), which consistently demonstrated microglial activation and behavioral inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiroshi Giga, Bin Ji, Kazuya Kikutani, Shuji Fukuda, Takashi Kitajima, Seishi Katsumata, Miho Matsumata, Tetsuya Suhara, Shigeto Yamawaki, Nobuaki Shime, Koji Hosokawa, Hidenori Aizawa &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pharmacological and Genetic Inhibition of Translocator Protein 18 kDa Ameliorated Neuroinflammation in Murine Endotoxemia Model&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; SHOCK (20) &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33351449/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[PubMed]&lt;/a&gt;  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.lww.com/shockjournal/Abstract/9000/Pharmacological_and_Genetic_Inhibition_of.97339.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Journal website]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene expression analysis showed that TSPO in the hippomcapus was induced following the systemic LPS injection, associated with an increase in pro-inflammatory cytokines such as tumor necrosis factor-a and interleukin-1b. Interestingly, pretreatment with the TSPO antagonist, ONO-2952, or germ-line deletion of the TSPO gene exhibited an anti-inflammatory effect with significant suppression of LPS-induced production of those cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These effects of ONO-2952 or TSPO knockout were associated with significant recovery from behavioral inhibition, as shown by improved locomotor activity in the open field analysis. We also observed that ONO-2952 pretreatment suppressed the LPS-induced activation of TSPO-expressing microglia in the hippocampus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;behaviors.png&#34; alt=&#34;TSPO suppression improved behavioral alteration with systemic inflammation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how we began to understand a critical role of TSPO in SAE. Based on this finding, monitoring TSPO activity, as well as the progress of sepsis and its sequelae in the animal model, would deepen our understanding of the underlying molecular mechanism of SAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychiatric sequelae of intensive care: a role of neuroinflammation</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/post/20200926/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 13:16:46 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/ja/post/20200926/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Physical stress such as infection and trauma, often causes a variety of outcome. COVID-19 outbreak in 2020 would likely result in an increase in intensive care survivors who would frequently develop anxiety, depression and PTSD as a part of post intensive care syndrome (PICS). Survival rates for critically ill patients are increasing as medical science advances, but with it PICS in survivors is becoming a major medical problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergent lines of evidence recently supported that physical and emotional stress induced inflammatory responses in the central nervous system. Microglia play a pivotal role in induction and expansion of the neuroinflammatory reactions. Activated microglia are known to secrete the signaling molecules such as reactive oxygen species (ROS) and cytokines, which mediates the interplay between neurons and glia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a collaborative study with Department of Emergency and Critical Care Medicine in Hiroshima University, We have just published a review paper which discusses recent advances in the studies on the role of translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO) in microglial activation and in stressor-related disorders associated with anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K Kikutani, H Giga, K Hosokawa, N Shime, H Aizawa, &lt;strong&gt;Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder.&lt;/strong&gt; Neurochem Int (2020), &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2020.104855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tspo.png&#34; alt=&#34;neuroinflammation and TSPO&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent studies collectively support the view that upregulation of TSPO in microglia in response to the various physical and mental stress underlies pathophysiology of psychiatric symptoms. Future study may enable us to make use of TSPO as a probe to monitor the chronic time course of the stressor-related disorders in the survivors from the intensitve care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
