<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</title>
    <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Neurobiology lab in Hiroshima University</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:06:31 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/images/logo_hu3a19eda7c46e3a038077b40a81977f92_85527_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habenula Project</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/habenula-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/habenula-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;development-of-the-animal-model-for-depression&#34;&gt;Development of the animal model for depression&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The habenula is a diencephalic nucleus regulating monoamines such as dopamine and serotonin. We recently found that pathological activation of the habenula led the mice to show depressive-like behaviors under acute and chronic stress. Analyses revealed that mice with hyperactivated habenula showed reduction in the number of c-Fos positive cells in the brain stem nuclei producing the serotonin and dopamine, indicating that activation of those monoaminergic neurons was reduced upon activation of the habenula. Thus, our working hypothesis is that habenular activation elicits  depressive-like behaviors by way of  modulating monoaminergic activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See details in the recent post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../post/20200918&#34;&gt;A novel gene Pcsk5 causing depressive-like behaviors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../post/20200829&#34;&gt;Dopamine transmission in stress-coping behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../post/20200512&#34;&gt;A role of human habenula in learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading Depression Project</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/spreading_depression-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/spreading_depression-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;neural-excitability-in-stroke-and-migraine&#34;&gt;Neural excitability in stroke and migraine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitatory neural transmission is primarily mediated by glutamate in the synapse. However, excess extracellular glutamate is rather harmful for the brain and sometimes worsens brain pathology in neurological disorders such as stroke and migraine. Such pathological activation of neural tissue some can be propagated like waves in the brain and affect the prognosis of those diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ischemic and hypoglycemic brain, in particular, has an increase in neural excitability and shows propagation of neuronal and glial depolarization, a phenomenon known as spreading depolarization (spreading depression). Lesion core with hypoxia, for example, releases excitatory molecules such as glutamate and potassium. These molecules diffuse outside the cells and, in turn, activate the neurons surrounding the lesion core. Propagation of such an excitatory wave results in further demand of energy essential to maintain the viability of the tissue at risk surround the lesion core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Spreading depolarization as killer wave&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, recent studies frequently reported that spreading depolarization occured in the cerebral cortex of the patients with stroke and migraine. To make matters worse, a report revealed that the prognosis in the patients with traumatic brain injury was negatively correlated with the number of spreading depolarization observed in a given period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, therapeutic intervention to suppress spreading depolarization will be in need to improve sequelae in stroke. To address this, Professor Kohichi Tanaka (Tokyo Medical and Dental University) and I focused on a role of the glial cells in the brain. Glial cells such as astrocytes act to determine levels of glutamate concentration outside cells. Since astrocytes regulate the extracellular glutamate level by the glutamate transporter which uptakes the extracellular glutamate, we hypothesize that glutamate transporter activity in the astrocytes determines a susceptibility of the brain to spreading depression. Recent analyses revealed that mutant mice lacking glutamate transporter GLT-1 in a subset of astrocytes in the cerebral cortex had increased sensitivity to spreading depression with altered kinetics in extracellular glutamate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results suggest that enhancement of the glutamate transporter in the astrocytes may suppress frequent spreading depression and improve neurological sequelae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See details in the recent post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/post/20200626/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New publication on spreading depression implicated in migraine!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sepsis Project</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/sepsis-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 15:31:48 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/sepsis-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a life-threatening dysfunction of multiple organs caused by a dysregulated host response to infection. Notably, sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. As SAE develops a wide variety of disorders in neural functions, ranging from delirium to long-term cognitive impairment, molecular mechanism underlying it remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergent lines of evidence recently supported that physical and emotional stress induced inflammatory responses in the central nervous system. Microglia play a pivotal role in induction and expansion of the neuroinflammatory reactions. Activated microglia are known to secrete the signaling molecules such as reactive oxygen species (ROS) and cytokines, which mediates the interplay between neurons and glia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin to understand a role of microglia in SAE by examining the function of mitochondrial protein, translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO). As it is upregulated in immune cells such as microglia, it has attracted a surge of interest as a biomarker of the inflammatory response in the CNS. Indeed, microglial activity seems to be under the regulation of TSPO, at least in part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By extending those studies, we hope to develop a novel category of drugs for the treatment of SAE and stressor-related disorder which might occurs in intensive care survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;iba1_tspo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Activation of microglia with expression of TSPO&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kikutani K, Giga H, Hosokawa K, Shime N, Aizawa H, &lt;strong&gt;Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder.&lt;/strong&gt; Neurochem Int. 2020, &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2020.104855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nozaki K, Ito H, Ohgidani M, Yamawaki Y, Sahin EH, Kitajima T, Katsumata S, Yamawaki S, Kato TA, Aizawa H. &lt;strong&gt;Antidepressant effect of the translocator protein antagonist ONO-2952 on mouse behaviors under chronic social defeat stress.&lt;/strong&gt;  Neuropharmacology. 2020 Jan 1;162:107835.
&lt;a href=&#34;10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.107835&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/authors/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/authors/skills/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Microscopy Project</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/microscopy-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/microscopy-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;microscopic-analysis-of-the-neural-structure&#34;&gt;Microscopic analysis of the neural structure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain consists of multiple brain regions with different functions. Since they interact to act as unified organ, visualization of the three dimensional organization of the gene/protein expression on neural circuits is indispensable. To address this, we are currently developing a novel fluorescent microscope which allows volumentric analysis of the nervous tissue with referring to the gene/protein expression.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicinal Herbs Project</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/herbs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/herbs-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;toward-a-biological-evidence-for-the-traditional-medicine-in-epilepsy&#34;&gt;Toward a biological evidence for the traditional medicine in epilepsy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medicinal herbs play a central role in treatment of diseases in Malawi. Despite its prevelance in the country, it remains elusive whether those herbs have anti-epileptic effect based on the modern biology. We collaborate with the researchers in Malawi to start examining an anti-epileptic effect of the extract from the medicinal herbs used by Malawian practitioner in treatment of epileptic patients. To this end, we use zebrafish, an animal model amenable for drug screening and molecular/behavioral analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manupulation of the neural circuit</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/tools-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/tools-circuit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;unraveling-the-neural-circuit-responsible-for-the-mental-and-neurological-diseases&#34;&gt;Unraveling the neural circuit responsible for the mental and neurological diseases&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain consists of multiple regions with different functions. To reveal the neural pathway delineating the specific symptoms in diseases, genetics must be one of the most powerful tool to examine the neural network based on the speciific cell types and pathways. This can be achieved by a combination of gene targeting and viral vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab developed such novel tools to target specific cell type such as glia for functional analyses. For example, we revealed a critical role of the astroglia in depressive-like behaviors and sleep disturbance by glia-specific viral vectors (Cui et al., J Neurosci, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology  allows to target specific pathway embedded in the brain with help of a combination of optics and genetics (optogenetics). Indeed, we showed optogenetic inhibition of the dopaminergic pathway in the brain had antidepressant effect in mice (Cui et al., J Neurosci, 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;optogenetics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Photo-inhibition of the dopaminergic pathways reduced despair behaviors in mice.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also successful in knocking out of the gene of our interest by combining the genome editing with viral vector. Specifically, it carries CRISPR/Cas9 cassette targeting the gene of our interest and target the brain regions, which enables the researcher to knock out the genes in any brain regions of the wildtype animals. This is how we could knock ou the gene without generating the knockout mouse line, which usually takes so long. Skipping such long processes in the experiment would facilitate the high throughput analyses of the gene functions in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/20200829/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Optogenetics and CRISPR/Cas9 unraveled a novel role of dopamine in stress-coping behaviors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;crispr.png&#34; alt=&#34;In vivo genome editing by combining CRIPR/Cas9 and viral vector&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal models for disorders in the brain</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/tools-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/project/tools-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;development-of-the-animal-model-for-depression&#34;&gt;Development of the animal model for depression&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The habenula is a diencephalic nucleus regulating monoamines such as dopamine and serotonin. We recently found that pathological activation of the habenula led the mice to show depressive-like behaviors under acute and chronic stress. Analyses revealed that mice with hyperactivated habenula showed reduction in the number of c-Fos positive cells in the brain stem nuclei producing the serotonin and dopamine, indicating that activation of those monoaminergic neurons was reduced upon activation of the habenula. Thus, our working hypothesis is that habenular activation elicits depressive-like behaviors by way of modulating monoaminergic activities.
&lt;img src=&#34;csds.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chronic social defeat stress&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link below for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/habenula-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Project: Role of habenula in depression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;killer-wave-in-the-damaged-brain-spreading-depression&#34;&gt;Killer wave in the damaged brain: spreading depression&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitatory neural transmission is primarily mediated by glutamate in the synapse. However, excess extracellular glutamate is rather harmful for the brain and sometimes worsens brain pathology in neurological disorders such as stroke and migraine. Such pathological activation of neural tissue some can be propagated like waves in the brain and affect the prognosis of those diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ischemic and hypoglycemic brain, in particular, has an increase in neural excitability and shows propagation of neuronal and glial depolarization, a phenomenon known as spreading depolarization (spreading depression). Lesion core with hypoxia, for example, releases excitatory molecules such as glutamate and potassium. These molecules diffuse outside the cells and, in turn, activate the neurons surrounding the lesion core. Propagation of such an excitatory wave results in further demand of energy essential to maintain the viability of the tissue at risk surround the lesion core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, recent studies frequently reported that spreading depolarization occured in the cerebral cortex of the patients with stroke and migraine. To make matters worse, a report revealed that the prognosis in the patients with traumatic brain injury was negatively correlated with the number of spreading depolarization observed in a given period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, therapeutic intervention to suppress spreading depolarization will be in need to improve sequelae in stroke. To address this, Professor Kohichi Tanaka (Tokyo Medical and Dental University) and I focused on a role of the glial cells in the brain. Glial cells such as astrocytes act to determine levels of glutamate concentration outside cells. Since astrocytes regulate the extracellular glutamate level by the glutamate transporter which uptakes the extracellular glutamate, we hypothesize that glutamate transporter activity in the astrocytes determines a susceptibility of the brain to spreading depression. Recent analyses revealed that mutant mice lacking glutamate transporter GLT-1 in a subset of astrocytes in the cerebral cortex had increased sensitivity to spreading depression with altered kinetics in extracellular glutamate.
&lt;img src=&#34;csd.png&#34; alt=&#34;Glutamate metabolism at the synapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link below  for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/post/20200626/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spreading depression implicated in migraine and stroke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-we-save-the-brain-from-critical-illness&#34;&gt;How do we save the brain from critical illness?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a life-threatening dysfunction of multiple organs caused by a dysregulated host response to infection. Notably, sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. As SAE develops a wide variety of disorders in neural functions, ranging from delirium to long-term cognitive impairment, molecular mechanism underlying it remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergent lines of evidence recently supported that physical and emotional stress induced inflammatory responses in the central nervous system. Microglia play a pivotal role in induction and expansion of the neuroinflammatory reactions. Activated microglia are known to secrete the signaling molecules such as reactive oxygen species (ROS) and cytokines, which mediates the interplay between neurons and glia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin to understand a role of microglia in SAE by examining the function of mitochondrial protein, translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO). As it is upregulated in immune cells such as microglia, it has attracted a surge of interest as a biomarker of the inflammatory response in the CNS. Indeed, microglial activity seems to be under the regulation of TSPO, at least in part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By extending those studies, we hope to develop a novel category of drugs for the treatment of SAE and stressor-related disorder which might occurs in intensive care survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;iba1_tspo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Activation of microglia with expression of TSPO&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/sepsis-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Project: Neurobiology of the brain with critical illness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kikutani K, Giga H, Hosokawa K, Shime N, Aizawa H, &lt;strong&gt;Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder.&lt;/strong&gt; Neurochem Int. 2020, &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2020.104855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New gene acting on microglia activated upon sepsis which needs critical care medicine.</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20201221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:06:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20201221/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stressors such as surgery, infection and injury lead to the pathological condition known as sepsis. Associate with the systemic inflammation, not only the visceral organs but the brain starts to respond and behave in an unusual way. Sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. The development of an effective strategy for early diagnosis and therapeutic intervention is essential for the prevention of poor prognosis of SAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO) is a mitochondrial protein implicated in inflammatory responses. Despite accumulating evidence that implicates TSPO in the neuroinflammatory response of the central nervous system, the possible role of TSPO in SAE remains unclear. In the current study, we addressed a role of TSPO in neuroinflammation using mice 24 h after systemic injection of lipopolysaccharide (LPS), which consistently demonstrated microglial activation and behavioral inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiroshi Giga, Bin Ji, Kazuya Kikutani, Shuji Fukuda, Takashi Kitajima, Seishi Katsumata, Miho Matsumata, Tetsuya Suhara, Shigeto Yamawaki, Nobuaki Shime, Koji Hosokawa, Hidenori Aizawa &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pharmacological and Genetic Inhibition of Translocator Protein 18 kDa Ameliorated Neuroinflammation in Murine Endotoxemia Model&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; SHOCK (20) &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33351449/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[PubMed]&lt;/a&gt;  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.lww.com/shockjournal/Abstract/9000/Pharmacological_and_Genetic_Inhibition_of.97339.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Journal website]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene expression analysis showed that TSPO in the hippomcapus was induced following the systemic LPS injection, associated with an increase in pro-inflammatory cytokines such as tumor necrosis factor-a and interleukin-1b. Interestingly, pretreatment with the TSPO antagonist, ONO-2952, or germ-line deletion of the TSPO gene exhibited an anti-inflammatory effect with significant suppression of LPS-induced production of those cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These effects of ONO-2952 or TSPO knockout were associated with significant recovery from behavioral inhibition, as shown by improved locomotor activity in the open field analysis. We also observed that ONO-2952 pretreatment suppressed the LPS-induced activation of TSPO-expressing microglia in the hippocampus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;behaviors.png&#34; alt=&#34;TSPO suppression improved behavioral alteration with systemic inflammation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how we began to understand a critical role of TSPO in SAE. Based on this finding, monitoring TSPO activity, as well as the progress of sepsis and its sequelae in the animal model, would deepen our understanding of the underlying molecular mechanism of SAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharmacological and Genetic Inhibition of Translocator Protein 18 kDa Ameliorated Neuroinflammation in Murine Endotoxemia Model</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-33351449/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-33351449/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New study on a novel microscope for 3D visualization of the brain structure with deep ultraviolet light</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20201029/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:51:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20201029/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deciphering the connectivity between brain regions is critical in understanding how the brain works. Three dimensional visualization of such networks of the neurons has been hampered by poor penetration of visible light into the large brain tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;duv.png&#34; alt=&#34;Deep UV light&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this, our group combined the serial sectioning of the tissue block to expose new surface of the brain with scanning by light. Collected image would be used for three dimensional reconstruction of the brain structure later in the offiline analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.10.27.342345v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deep ultraviolet light based wide-field fluorescence microscope for brain imaging, preprint available in bioRxiv (doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.27.342345)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since visible light excites the fluorescent label out of focus, which makes the image blurred, we applied light to a limited optical plane at the surface of the exposed tissue block. Deep ultraviolet (DUV) light loses its power quickly after it reaches at the plane within 10-20 µm from the surface so that the image consists of the emitted light coming from the plane in focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;schematics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Workflow in DUV imaging&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is combined with motorized optics which enables scanning wide field of view to image the large brain tissue for three dimensional reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dii.png&#34; alt=&#34;Imaging neural pathways in the animals brain&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We applied this technique to the brain samples of small animals expressing green fluorescent protein and lipophilic dye in the neural pathways of mice and zebrafish. We are currently screening the fluorescent proteins and dyes compatible with this technology to widen the area for further application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, DUV imaging is quite cost-effective according to the simplicity of the optical setup. This is advantageous for the high throughput analyses with multple setups in the lab over the pre-existing expensive solution such as light-sheet and two-photon microscopies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychiatric sequelae of intensive care: a role of neuroinflammation</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200926/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 13:16:46 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200926/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Physical stress such as infection and trauma, often causes a variety of outcome. COVID-19 outbreak in 2020 would likely result in an increase in intensive care survivors who would frequently develop anxiety, depression and PTSD as a part of post intensive care syndrome (PICS). Survival rates for critically ill patients are increasing as medical science advances, but with it PICS in survivors is becoming a major medical problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergent lines of evidence recently supported that physical and emotional stress induced inflammatory responses in the central nervous system. Microglia play a pivotal role in induction and expansion of the neuroinflammatory reactions. Activated microglia are known to secrete the signaling molecules such as reactive oxygen species (ROS) and cytokines, which mediates the interplay between neurons and glia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a collaborative study with Department of Emergency and Critical Care Medicine in Hiroshima University, We have just published a review paper which discusses recent advances in the studies on the role of translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO) in microglial activation and in stressor-related disorders associated with anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K Kikutani, H Giga, K Hosokawa, N Shime, H Aizawa, &lt;strong&gt;Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder.&lt;/strong&gt; Neurochem Int (2020), &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2020.104855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tspo.png&#34; alt=&#34;neuroinflammation and TSPO&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent studies collectively support the view that upregulation of TSPO in microglia in response to the various physical and mental stress underlies pathophysiology of psychiatric symptoms. Future study may enable us to make use of TSPO as a probe to monitor the chronic time course of the stressor-related disorders in the survivors from the intensitve care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication on a novel gene causing depressive-like behaviors</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200918/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 16:53:13 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have just published a paper which identified a novel gene Pcsk5 acting on immune reaction in the mouse brain. Chronic stress activated this gene, which led to the subsequent activation of the other genes MMPs causing remodeling of the extracellular matrix. Since immune cell such as monocyte and microglia started to be activated and move more actively upon remodeling of extracellular matrix, Neurons seems to produce Pcsk5 seems to induce neuroinflammation in response to the chronic stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41386-020-00843-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our publication in the Neuropsychopharmacology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/system/files/149927/20200916_pr01.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Press release from Hiroshima University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amed.go.jp/news/release_20200917-01.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Press release from AMED&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, this protein turned out to be localize to the small area in the brain called habenula. This region attracts a surge of interest according to its role in regulation of central monoaminergic system. Monoamines such as dopamine and serotonin are known to be a basis of pathophysiology of depression and paharmacological action of antidepressant available currently. Since this area is excited when the animal perceives disappointment and punishment, it is proposed that the habenula may act as a negative source of reinforcement signal in the brain to control our behavioral strategy for survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Pcsk5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chronic hyper-activation of the habenula via PCSK5-MMP ignaling pathway&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking the current results into consideration, we may begin to understand how the transient activation of the habenula via punishment or disappointment can be chronic via changes in extracellular environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of proprotein convertase in the mouse habenula causes depressive-like behaviors through remodeling of extracellular matrix</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32942293/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32942293/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32980493/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32980493/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication on dopamine transmission in stress-coping behavior</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200829/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 17:47:48 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200829/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently published a paper on a role of neurotransmitter dopamine in stress-coping behavior in Journal of Neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jneurosci.org/content/early/2020/08/26/JNEUROSCI.0444-20.2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our publication in the Journal of Neurosience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the animals encounter the environmental threat as stressor, we can think of two distinct strategies to cope with it. One is to try to overcome it by exploring actively and be against it, the other is to avoid and refrain from being close to it passively. Active and passive coping of the stress would be the basis to determine the behavioral strategies upon exposure to the stressor. Since maladaptation to the stress predispose the psychiatric disorders such as depression and anxiety, understanding the molecular mechanism underlying it is indispensable for the development of therapeutic intervention for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this, we focused on neurotransmitter dopamine which plays pivotal roles in decision making and reinforcement of the behaviors. We developed a fine carbon fiber electrode to scan the brain region called nucleus accumbens to examine how the dopamine release change when the mice changed stress-coping behaviors under the inescapable stress such as tail suspension. We found that reduction of dopamine release in this area precede the initation of escape behavior, implicating the dopaminergic transmission to the decision making under the stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fscv.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sub-milli second measurement of extracellular dopamine by fast scanning cyclic voltammetry&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check the causal effect of reduced dopamine release on mouse behaviors, we took two indepdent strategies. Optogenetic inhibitoin of dopaminergic fibers in the nucleus accumbens allowed inhibition of dopamine release at any time you want thru illumination of blue light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;optogenetics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Optogenetic manupulatin of the dopaminergic pathway&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tool we used this time is CRISPR/Cas9 which deletes the receptors for dopaminergic transmission efficiently in the mouse brain by way of viral vector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;crispr.png&#34; alt=&#34;In vivo genome editing of dopaminergic receptors by CRISPR/Cas9 technology &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both experiments proved that impaired dopaminergic transmission caused induction of escape behavior during tail suspension stress. Through this study, we are pleased to establish three important tools which must be useful for futre study: fast scanning cyclic voltammetry, optogenetics and CRISPR/Cas9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to discuss these new tools in the post comming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dopaminergic signaling in the nucleus accumbens modulates stress-coping strategies during inescapable stress</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32847967/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32847967/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication on spreading depression implicated in migraine and stroke</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200626/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:40:12 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200626/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group published a paper in the journal GLIA on a role of glutamate in spreading depression, a pre-clinical model for the aura preceding the migraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/glia.23874&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our publication in GLIA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/news/58665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Press release from the Hiroshima University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreading depression is a propagating wave of neuronal and glial excitation under the pathological conditions. Studies suggested that it is found in the neurological disorders such as migraine and ischemic stroke. In particular, one third of migrainers are known to show neurological deficits (e.g., visual defect) in advance of the headache. Despite its clinical significance, molecular mechanism underlying the spreading depression reamins elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glutamate, an amino acid, acts as neurotransmitter in the brain. Upon binding of glutamate to the receptors, it modulates the flow of channel across the cell membrane of neurons to let it excited. This is how the glutamte facilitates the communication between neurons connecting with axonal fiber. If it acts too much with excessively high level in concentration in the extracellular space, it could be pathological and lead to the disorganized neural network activity and cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hypothesize that glutamate metabolism underlies the spreading depression. To address this, we examined the multiple knockout mice lacking any of the glutamate transporters, key modulators of the extracellular concentration of glutamate. Electrophysiological analｓysis revealed that mice lacking one of the glutamate transporters GLT-1 exhibited highest susceptibility to the spreading depression among mutant mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ephys.png&#34; alt=&#34;Electrophysiological analysis in the mutants&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address a role of GLT-1 in glutamate metabolism, we developed glutamate biosensor which measure the glutamate concentration 4 times in a second. Mice lacking GLT-1 exhibited accumulation of extracellular glutamate more quickly than control, suggesting that GLT-1 plays a critical role in clearing glutamate from the extracellular space to maintain the ambient condition there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;biosensor.png&#34; alt=&#34;Measurement of extracellular glutamate using biosensor&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, these results indicate a drug enhancing GLT-1 function might be a candidate to treat the migrain by reducing the susceptibility to spreading depression. We hope to screen such drug using model animals soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International collaboration</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200613/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 06:04:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We welcome the international students and collaboration to facilitate our progress in neuroscience. With the international background in Hiroshima, our lab encourages the students and researcher to develop their careers by scholarship and grants. Indeed, our lab members from a variety of countries all over the world weekly hold the meeting for the progress report and journal club. We also discuss the textbook to help the international students to understand the basics in neuroscience, optics and data science periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;member.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lab members from the countries all over the world&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, our research is enpowered by collaborations with researcher all over the world. For example, we have invited the researcher from US, UK and China to discuss and perform experiments together to develop new technologies in neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an international and research university, Hiroshima university helps the students and researcher who do not speak Japanese to learn Japanese and Japanese culture through specific classes and socials (international luncheon parties).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/#contact&#34;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in joining us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scholarship supporting the graduate course in Hiroshima</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200601/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 22:18:03 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200601/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our lab currently work with six graduate students in total. Scholarship and support by the university primarily allow them to concentrate on their own project for the theses. We were pleased to see the students win the scholarship based on their achievement to develop the carreer in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication on a role of human habenula in learning</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200512/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:22:34 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200512/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Habenula is an evolutionarily conserved structure in the brain and regulates the central monoaminergic metabolism. Despite a surge of interest on the habenula in neuroscience, function of the human habenula remains unclear. Dr. Yoshino led the project members including our lab performed functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) analysis during a contextual learning task.The left and right habenula were activated during aversive outcomes and the activation was associated with aversive prediction errors. Furthermore, dynamic causal modeling (DCM) analyses demonstrated the left and right habenula to the left and right hippocampus connections during the presentation of contextual stimuli. These findings serve to highlight the neural mechanisms that may be relevant to understanding the broader relationship between the habenula and learning processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2020.00165&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2020.00165&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dogwood blooms</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200501_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 19:21:30 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200501_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t see undergraduate students recently in the campus due to the COVID-19, and it is a pity not to see newcomers in this April. Dogweed bloom in front of the building as before reminds us of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our recent review paper recognized as one of the most downloaded paper!!</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200501/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 19:04:28 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200501/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wrote a review paper in Psychiatry and Clinical Neuroscience on a role of the habenula in depressioin. This is a recent update of the small brain structure called habenula in modulation of the mood in our daily life by graduate student Zhu-san and me. We are happy to hear that our paper turned out to be one of the most downloaded paper in the journal during 2018-2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online lab meeting</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200429/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 21:51:20 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We started to hold weekly lab meeting for the progress report and journal club online over zoom. This is because we tried not to make members gathered at the same room to have lunch meeting. I found the online meeting still worked fine and we are getting familiar with it after several trials.
Photo by Campaign Creators on Unsplash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Neurobiology #Hiroshima #Brain #神経 #広島 #脳&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online histology class in Hiroshima</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200425/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 16:35:11 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200425/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the influence of COVID-19, we set out our histology class using online tools such as Microsoft Teams and BB9. With having a chat with undergraduate students over MS Teams, we hope to discuss cellular organization of the organs in human as before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social sharing with Neurobiology lab in Hiroshima</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200418/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 10:41:53 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We started new social sharing with twitter and facebook to post! Check the new post shared by them soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Sharingbutton Twitter --&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;resp-sharing-button__link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NeurobiolLabHS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;resp-sharing-button resp-sharing-button--twitter resp-sharing-button--medium&#34;&gt;&lt;div aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; class=&#34;resp-sharing-button__icon resp-sharing-button__icon--solid&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M23.44 4.83c-.8.37-1.5.38-2.22.02.93-.56.98-.96 1.32-2.02-.88.52-1.86.9-2.9 1.1-.82-.88-2-1.43-3.3-1.43-2.5 0-4.55 2.04-4.55 4.54 0 .36.03.7.1 1.04-3.77-.2-7.12-2-9.36-4.75-.4.67-.6 1.45-.6 2.3 0 1.56.8 2.95 2 3.77-.74-.03-1.44-.23-2.05-.57v.06c0 2.2 1.56 4.03 3.64 4.44-.67.2-1.37.2-2.06.08.58 1.8 2.26 3.12 4.25 3.16C5.78 18.1 3.37 18.74 1 18.46c2 1.3 4.4 2.04 6.97 2.04 8.35 0 12.92-6.92 12.92-12.93 0-.2 0-.4-.02-.6.9-.63 1.96-1.22 2.56-2.14z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Twitter&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!-- Sharingbutton Facebook --&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;resp-sharing-button__link&#34; href=&#34;https://facebook.com/NeurobiolHiroshima&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;Facebook&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;resp-sharing-button resp-sharing-button--facebook resp-sharing-button--medium&#34;&gt;&lt;div aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; class=&#34;resp-sharing-button__icon resp-sharing-button__icon--solid&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M18.77 7.46H14.5v-1.9c0-.9.6-1.1 1-1.1h3V.5h-4.33C10.24.5 9.5 3.44 9.5 5.32v2.15h-3v4h3v12h5v-12h3.85l.42-4z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Facebook&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/NeurobiolLabHS&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/NeurobiolLabHS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/NeurobiolHiroshima&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/NeurobiolHiroshima&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New faculty from Germany</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200417/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 14:45:28 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/post/20200417/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We welcome new faculty from Germany. Dr. Handa and I worked previously in RIKEN Brain Science Institute in a collaborative way. While I moved to the new lab in Tokyo Medical and Dental University, he accomplished his work on a role of the rat prefrontal cortex in decision making as published in Cerebral Cortex (2017). Now that he elaborated his physiological technique using two photon microscopy, we look forward to collaborate with him again to make significant progress in Hiroshima.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antidepressant effect of the translocator protein antagonist ONO-2952 on mouse behaviors under chronic social defeat stress</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-31682855/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-31682855/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antidepressant effect of the translocator protein antagonist ONO-2952 on mouse behaviors under chronic social defeat stress</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-31682855/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-31682855/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glial Glutamate Transporter GLT-1 Determines Susceptibility to Spreading Depression in the Mouse Cerebral Cortex</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32585762/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32585762/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of the Habenula for Avoidance Learning Including Contextual Cues in the Human Brain: A Preliminary fMRI Study</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-32477084/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-32477084/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of the Habenula for Avoidance Learning Including Contextual Cues in the Human Brain: A Preliminary fMRI Study</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32477084/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-32477084/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phospholipase C-related catalytically inactive protein regulates lipopolysaccharide-induced hypothalamic inflammation-mediated anorexia in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-31589911/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-31589911/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phospholipase C-related catalytically inactive protein regulates lipopolysaccharide-induced hypothalamic inflammation-mediated anorexia in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-31589911/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-31589911/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward an understanding of the habenula&#39;s various roles in human depression</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-31131942/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-31131942/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward an understanding of the habenula&#39;s various roles in human depression</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-31131942/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-31131942/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Region-specific deletions of the glutamate transporter GLT1 differentially affect seizure activity and neurodegeneration in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-29214672/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-29214672/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Region-specific deletions of the glutamate transporter GLT1 differentially affect seizure activity and neurodegeneration in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-29214672/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-29214672/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sodium butyrate abolishes lipopolysaccharide-induced depression-like behaviors and hippocampal microglial activation in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-29229502/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-29229502/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sodium butyrate abolishes lipopolysaccharide-induced depression-like behaviors and hippocampal microglial activation in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-29229502/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-29229502/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative splicing in the C-terminal tail of Cav2.1 is essential for preventing a neurological disease in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-28510727/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-28510727/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative splicing in the C-terminal tail of Cav2.1 is essential for preventing a neurological disease in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-28510727/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-28510727/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene cassette knock-in in mammalian cells and zygotes by enhanced MMEJ</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-27894274/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-27894274/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene cassette knock-in in mammalian cells and zygotes by enhanced MMEJ</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-27894274/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-27894274/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impaired striatal dopamine release in homozygous Vps35 D620N knock-in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-28173004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-28173004/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impaired striatal dopamine release in homozygous Vps35 D620N knock-in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-28173004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-28173004/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuronal Heterotopias Affect the Activities of Distant Brain Areas and Lead to Behavioral Deficits</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-26354912/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-26354912/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuronal Heterotopias Affect the Activities of Distant Brain Areas and Lead to Behavioral Deficits</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-26354912/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-26354912/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astroglial glutamate transporter deficiency increases synaptic excitability and leads to pathological repetitive behaviors in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-25662838/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-25662838/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astroglial glutamate transporter deficiency increases synaptic excitability and leads to pathological repetitive behaviors in mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-25662838/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-25662838/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glial dysfunction in the mouse habenula causes depressive-like behaviors and sleep disturbance</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-25471567/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-25471567/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glial dysfunction in the mouse habenula causes depressive-like behaviors and sleep disturbance</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-25471567/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-25471567/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The habenulo-raphe serotonergic circuit encodes an aversive expectation value essential for adaptive active avoidance of danger</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-25467985/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-25467985/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The habenulo-raphe serotonergic circuit encodes an aversive expectation value essential for adaptive active avoidance of danger</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-25467985/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-25467985/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperactivation of the habenula as a link between depression and sleep disturbance</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-24339810/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-24339810/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperactivation of the habenula as a link between depression and sleep disturbance</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-24339810/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-24339810/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging of neural ensemble for the retrieval of a learned behavioral program</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23684786/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23684786/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging of neural ensemble for the retrieval of a learned behavioral program</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23684786/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23684786/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reward-modulated motor information in identified striatum neurons</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23785137/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23785137/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reward-modulated motor information in identified striatum neurons</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23785137/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23785137/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and anxiety regulation by conserved affective circuits</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23664609/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23664609/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and anxiety regulation by conserved affective circuits</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23664609/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23664609/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The synchronous activity of lateral habenular neurons is essential for regulating hippocampal theta oscillation</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23678132/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23678132/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The synchronous activity of lateral habenular neurons is essential for regulating hippocampal theta oscillation</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23678132/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23678132/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habenula and the asymmetric development of the vertebrate brain</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23086722/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-23086722/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habenula and the asymmetric development of the vertebrate brain</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23086722/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-23086722/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular characterization of the subnuclei in rat habenula</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-22700183/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-22700183/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular characterization of the subnuclei in rat habenula</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-22700183/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-22700183/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phylogeny and ontogeny of the habenular structure</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-22203792/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-22203792/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The habenula is crucial for experience-dependent modification of fear responses in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-20935642/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-20935642/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The habenula is crucial for experience-dependent modification of fear responses in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-20935642/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-20935642/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the zebrafish ventral habenula as a homolog of the mammalian lateral habenula</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-20107084/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-20107084/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the zebrafish ventral habenula as a homolog of the mammalian lateral habenula</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-20107084/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-20107084/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcircuitry coordination of cortical motor information in self-initiation of voluntary movements</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-19898469/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-19898469/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcircuitry coordination of cortical motor information in self-initiation of voluntary movements</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-19898469/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-19898469/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of the mouse amygdala as revealed by enhanced green fluorescent protein gene transfer by means of in utero electroporation</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-19107806/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-19107806/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of the mouse amygdala as revealed by enhanced green fluorescent protein gene transfer by means of in utero electroporation</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-19107806/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-19107806/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transgenic technology for visualization and manipulation of the neural circuits controlling behavior in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-18430169/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-18430169/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transgenic technology for visualization and manipulation of the neural circuits controlling behavior in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-18430169/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-18430169/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic single-cell mosaic analysis implicates ephrinB2 reverse signaling in projections from the posterior tectum to the hindbrain in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-17507550/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-17507550/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic single-cell mosaic analysis implicates ephrinB2 reverse signaling in projections from the posterior tectum to the hindbrain in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-17507550/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-17507550/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of two distinct classes of neurons by gad2 and zic1 promoter/enhancer elements in the dorsal hindbrain of developing zebrafish reveals neuronal connectivity related to the auditory and lateral line systems</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-17279576/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-17279576/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of two distinct classes of neurons by gad2 and zic1 promoter/enhancer elements in the dorsal hindbrain of developing zebrafish reveals neuronal connectivity related to the auditory and lateral line systems</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-17279576/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-17279576/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporally regulated asymmetric neurogenesis causes left-right difference in the zebrafish habenular structures</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-17199043/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-17199043/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporally regulated asymmetric neurogenesis causes left-right difference in the zebrafish habenular structures</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-17199043/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-17199043/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laterotopic representation of left-right information onto the dorso-ventral axis of a zebrafish midbrain target nucleus</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-15694307/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-15694307/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of the amygdalohypothalamic projection in the mouse embryonic forebrain</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-15232736/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-15232736/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of the amygdalohypothalamic projection in the mouse embryonic forebrain</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-15232736/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-15232736/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of the coding sequences of mouse homologues of KIAA gene: II. The complete nucleotide sequences of 400 mouse KIAA-homologous cDNAs identified by screening of terminal sequences of cDNA clones randomly sampled from size-fractionated libraries</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-12693553/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-12693553/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of the coding sequences of mouse homologues of KIAA gene: II. The complete nucleotide sequences of 400 mouse KIAA-homologous cDNAs identified by screening of terminal sequences of cDNA clones randomly sampled from size-fractionated libraries</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-12693553/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-12693553/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impaired cell cycle control of neuronal precursor cells in the neocortical primordium of presenilin-1-deficient mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-12391611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/content/publication/pmid-12391611/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impaired cell cycle control of neuronal precursor cells in the neocortical primordium of presenilin-1-deficient mice</title>
      <link>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-12391611/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aizawalab.github.io/neurobio/en/publication/pmid-12391611/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
