<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | AIZAWA lab in Hiroshima exploring the brain machinery and its disorders</title>
    <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Neurobiology lab in Hiroshima University</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 15:31:48 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/images/logo_hu3a19eda7c46e3a038077b40a81977f92_85527_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habenula Project</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/habenula-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/habenula-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;development-of-the-animal-model-for-depression&#34;&gt;Development of the animal model for depression&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The habenula is a diencephalic nucleus regulating monoamines such as dopamine and serotonin. We recently found that pathological activation of the habenula led the mice to show depressive-like behaviors under acute and chronic stress. Analyses revealed that mice with hyperactivated habenula showed reduction in the number of c-Fos positive cells in the brain stem nuclei producing the serotonin and dopamine, indicating that activation of those monoaminergic neurons was reduced upon activation of the habenula. Thus, our working hypothesis is that habenular activation elicits  depressive-like behaviors by way of  modulating monoaminergic activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See details in the recent post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../post/20200918&#34;&gt;A novel gene Pcsk5 causing depressive-like behaviors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../post/20200829&#34;&gt;Dopamine transmission in stress-coping behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../post/20200512&#34;&gt;A role of human habenula in learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading Depression Project</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/spreading_depression-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/spreading_depression-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;neural-excitability-in-stroke-and-migraine&#34;&gt;Neural excitability in stroke and migraine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitatory neural transmission is primarily mediated by glutamate in the synapse. However, excess extracellular glutamate is rather harmful for the brain and sometimes worsens brain pathology in neurological disorders such as stroke and migraine. Such pathological activation of neural tissue some can be propagated like waves in the brain and affect the prognosis of those diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ischemic and hypoglycemic brain, in particular, has an increase in neural excitability and shows propagation of neuronal and glial depolarization, a phenomenon known as spreading depolarization (spreading depression). Lesion core with hypoxia, for example, releases excitatory molecules such as glutamate and potassium. These molecules diffuse outside the cells and, in turn, activate the neurons surrounding the lesion core. Propagation of such an excitatory wave results in further demand of energy essential to maintain the viability of the tissue at risk surround the lesion core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Spreading depolarization as killer wave&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, recent studies frequently reported that spreading depolarization occured in the cerebral cortex of the patients with stroke and migraine. To make matters worse, a report revealed that the prognosis in the patients with traumatic brain injury was negatively correlated with the number of spreading depolarization observed in a given period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, therapeutic intervention to suppress spreading depolarization will be in need to improve sequelae in stroke. To address this, Professor Kohichi Tanaka (Tokyo Medical and Dental University) and I focused on a role of the glial cells in the brain. Glial cells such as astrocytes act to determine levels of glutamate concentration outside cells. Since astrocytes regulate the extracellular glutamate level by the glutamate transporter which uptakes the extracellular glutamate, we hypothesize that glutamate transporter activity in the astrocytes determines a susceptibility of the brain to spreading depression. Recent analyses revealed that mutant mice lacking glutamate transporter GLT-1 in a subset of astrocytes in the cerebral cortex had increased sensitivity to spreading depression with altered kinetics in extracellular glutamate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results suggest that enhancement of the glutamate transporter in the astrocytes may suppress frequent spreading depression and improve neurological sequelae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See details in the recent post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/post/20200626/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New publication on spreading depression implicated in migraine!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicinal Herbs Project</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/herbs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/herbs-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;toward-a-biological-evidence-for-the-traditional-medicine-in-epilepsy&#34;&gt;Toward a biological evidence for the traditional medicine in epilepsy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medicinal herbs play a central role in treatment of diseases in Malawi. Despite its prevelance in the country, it remains elusive whether those herbs have anti-epileptic effect based on the modern biology. We collaborate with the researchers in Malawi to start examining an anti-epileptic effect of the extract from the medicinal herbs used by Malawian practitioner in treatment of epileptic patients. To this end, we use zebrafish, an animal model amenable for drug screening and molecular/behavioral analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manupulation of the neural circuit</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/tools-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/tools-circuit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;unraveling-the-neural-circuit-responsible-for-the-mental-and-neurological-diseases&#34;&gt;Unraveling the neural circuit responsible for the mental and neurological diseases&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain consists of multiple regions with different functions. To reveal the neural pathway delineating the specific symptoms in diseases, genetics must be one of the most powerful tool to examine the neural network based on the speciific cell types and pathways. This can be achieved by a combination of gene targeting and viral vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab developed such novel tools to target specific cell type such as glia for functional analyses. For example, we revealed a critical role of the astroglia in depressive-like behaviors and sleep disturbance by glia-specific viral vectors (Cui et al., J Neurosci, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology  allows to target specific pathway embedded in the brain with help of a combination of optics and genetics (optogenetics). Indeed, we showed optogenetic inhibition of the dopaminergic pathway in the brain had antidepressant effect in mice (Cui et al., J Neurosci, 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;optogenetics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Photo-inhibition of the dopaminergic pathways reduced despair behaviors in mice.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also successful in knocking out of the gene of our interest by combining the genome editing with viral vector. Specifically, it carries CRISPR/Cas9 cassette targeting the gene of our interest and target the brain regions, which enables the researcher to knock out the genes in any brain regions of the wildtype animals. This is how we could knock ou the gene without generating the knockout mouse line, which usually takes so long. Skipping such long processes in the experiment would facilitate the high throughput analyses of the gene functions in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/20200829/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Optogenetics and CRISPR/Cas9 unraveled a novel role of dopamine in stress-coping behaviors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;crispr.png&#34; alt=&#34;In vivo genome editing by combining CRIPR/Cas9 and viral vector&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal models for disorders in the brain</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/tools-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/tools-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;development-of-the-animal-model-for-depression&#34;&gt;Development of the animal model for depression&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The habenula is a diencephalic nucleus regulating monoamines such as dopamine and serotonin. We recently found that pathological activation of the habenula led the mice to show depressive-like behaviors under acute and chronic stress. Analyses revealed that mice with hyperactivated habenula showed reduction in the number of c-Fos positive cells in the brain stem nuclei producing the serotonin and dopamine, indicating that activation of those monoaminergic neurons was reduced upon activation of the habenula. Thus, our working hypothesis is that habenular activation elicits depressive-like behaviors by way of modulating monoaminergic activities.
&lt;img src=&#34;csds.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chronic social defeat stress&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link below for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/habenula-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Project: Role of habenula in depression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;killer-wave-in-the-damaged-brain-spreading-depression&#34;&gt;Killer wave in the damaged brain: spreading depression&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitatory neural transmission is primarily mediated by glutamate in the synapse. However, excess extracellular glutamate is rather harmful for the brain and sometimes worsens brain pathology in neurological disorders such as stroke and migraine. Such pathological activation of neural tissue some can be propagated like waves in the brain and affect the prognosis of those diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ischemic and hypoglycemic brain, in particular, has an increase in neural excitability and shows propagation of neuronal and glial depolarization, a phenomenon known as spreading depolarization (spreading depression). Lesion core with hypoxia, for example, releases excitatory molecules such as glutamate and potassium. These molecules diffuse outside the cells and, in turn, activate the neurons surrounding the lesion core. Propagation of such an excitatory wave results in further demand of energy essential to maintain the viability of the tissue at risk surround the lesion core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, recent studies frequently reported that spreading depolarization occured in the cerebral cortex of the patients with stroke and migraine. To make matters worse, a report revealed that the prognosis in the patients with traumatic brain injury was negatively correlated with the number of spreading depolarization observed in a given period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, therapeutic intervention to suppress spreading depolarization will be in need to improve sequelae in stroke. To address this, Professor Kohichi Tanaka (Tokyo Medical and Dental University) and I focused on a role of the glial cells in the brain. Glial cells such as astrocytes act to determine levels of glutamate concentration outside cells. Since astrocytes regulate the extracellular glutamate level by the glutamate transporter which uptakes the extracellular glutamate, we hypothesize that glutamate transporter activity in the astrocytes determines a susceptibility of the brain to spreading depression. Recent analyses revealed that mutant mice lacking glutamate transporter GLT-1 in a subset of astrocytes in the cerebral cortex had increased sensitivity to spreading depression with altered kinetics in extracellular glutamate.
&lt;img src=&#34;csd.png&#34; alt=&#34;Glutamate metabolism at the synapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link below  for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/post/20200626/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spreading depression implicated in migraine and stroke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-we-save-the-brain-from-critical-illness&#34;&gt;How do we save the brain from critical illness?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a life-threatening dysfunction of multiple organs caused by a dysregulated host response to infection. Notably, sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. As SAE develops a wide variety of disorders in neural functions, ranging from delirium to long-term cognitive impairment, molecular mechanism underlying it remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergent lines of evidence recently supported that physical and emotional stress induced inflammatory responses in the central nervous system. Microglia play a pivotal role in induction and expansion of the neuroinflammatory reactions. Activated microglia are known to secrete the signaling molecules such as reactive oxygen species (ROS) and cytokines, which mediates the interplay between neurons and glia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin to understand a role of microglia in SAE by examining the function of mitochondrial protein, translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO). As it is upregulated in immune cells such as microglia, it has attracted a surge of interest as a biomarker of the inflammatory response in the CNS. Indeed, microglial activity seems to be under the regulation of TSPO, at least in part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By extending those studies, we hope to develop a novel category of drugs for the treatment of SAE and stressor-related disorder which might occurs in intensive care survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;iba1_tspo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Activation of microglia with expression of TSPO&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/sepsis-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Project: Neurobiology of the brain with critical illness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kikutani K, Giga H, Hosokawa K, Shime N, Aizawa H, &lt;strong&gt;Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder.&lt;/strong&gt; Neurochem Int. 2020, &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2020.104855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Microscopy Project</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/microscopy-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/microscopy-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;microscopic-analysis-of-the-neural-structure&#34;&gt;Microscopic analysis of the neural structure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain consists of multiple brain regions with different functions. Since they interact to act as unified organ, visualization of the three dimensional organization of the gene/protein expression on neural circuits is indispensable. To address this, we are currently developing a novel fluorescent microscope which allows volumentric analysis of the nervous tissue with referring to the gene/protein expression.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sepsis Project</title>
      <link>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/sepsis-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 15:31:48 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurobio.hiroshima-u.ac.jp/en/project/sepsis-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a life-threatening dysfunction of multiple organs caused by a dysregulated host response to infection. Notably, sepsis-associated encephalopathy (SAE) is a diffuse brain dysfunction associated with sepsis. As SAE develops a wide variety of disorders in neural functions, ranging from delirium to long-term cognitive impairment, molecular mechanism underlying it remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergent lines of evidence recently supported that physical and emotional stress induced inflammatory responses in the central nervous system. Microglia play a pivotal role in induction and expansion of the neuroinflammatory reactions. Activated microglia are known to secrete the signaling molecules such as reactive oxygen species (ROS) and cytokines, which mediates the interplay between neurons and glia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin to understand a role of microglia in SAE by examining the function of mitochondrial protein, translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO). As it is upregulated in immune cells such as microglia, it has attracted a surge of interest as a biomarker of the inflammatory response in the CNS. Indeed, microglial activity seems to be under the regulation of TSPO, at least in part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By extending those studies, we hope to develop a novel category of drugs for the treatment of SAE and stressor-related disorder which might occurs in intensive care survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;iba1_tspo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Activation of microglia with expression of TSPO&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kikutani K, Giga H, Hosokawa K, Shime N, Aizawa H, &lt;strong&gt;Microglial translocator protein and stressor-related disorder.&lt;/strong&gt; Neurochem Int. 2020, &lt;em&gt;in press&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2020.104855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nozaki K, Ito H, Ohgidani M, Yamawaki Y, Sahin EH, Kitajima T, Katsumata S, Yamawaki S, Kato TA, Aizawa H. &lt;strong&gt;Antidepressant effect of the translocator protein antagonist ONO-2952 on mouse behaviors under chronic social defeat stress.&lt;/strong&gt;  Neuropharmacology. 2020 Jan 1;162:107835.
&lt;a href=&#34;10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.107835&#34;&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
